Zackary Santana

Miami, FL | zsant014@fiu.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/zackary-santana | https://zackaryjamessantana.com | https://attach.fly.dev

Summary

3+ years of experience as a passionate software developer that's worked on large scale teams using Agile methodologies. Experience with working in a constantly changing development environment with continuous development/deployment. Loves working on web applications, frontend or backend, as well as improving UI/UX, Docker, and Database related work!

Education

Florida International University

Expected Graduation: April 2023*

• Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.6

• Advance UNIX Programming, Algorithm Techniques, Artificial Intelligence, Data Mining, Data Structures, Database Administration, Database Management, Human-Computer Interaction, Software Engineering

Work Experience

Software Engineer Intern

June 2022 – August 2022

MongoDB

- Worked on a **Scrum Agile** team for MongoDB's internal **CI/CD** testing tool, Evergreen.
- Programmed in Golang to augment the CLI, create and manage REST endpoints, and adjust the lifecycle of hosts/tasks
- Created capabilities for a test suite to have options to restart a subset of tests to reduce machine usage by up to 80% for certain restarts. (https://github.com/evergreen-ci/evergreen)

Software Engineer Intern

June 2021 – August 2021

MetLife

- Managed/maintained a frontend **Angular.js** application displaying real-time information, reducing load time from 10s to 1s.
- Organized the backend **Restify** that interacted with a **MongoDB** that pinged endpoints to test status of **Java Virtual Machines**.
- Engaged in a SAFe Agile team that made use of scrum to keep track with the day-to-day process.

Director of Technology/Code (https://flow.fly.dev)

January 2021 – Present

UPE - Development Program

- Created and managed a responsive and adaptive website for an organization with 8000+ members.
- **React.js and Remix.js** were used for Server-Side Rendering (SSR) and caching. **Strapi** was used to implement a custom Content Management System (**CMS**). **Docker** and **Flyctl** were used for deployment.

Workshop Organizer & Judge

August 2020 - Present

ShellHacks - Hackathon

- Tailor made and hosted workshops for **Florida's largest hackathon**, **ShellHacks**, which has over **50** sponsors like Microsoft, Google, Amazon, and Facebook and **1000**+ participants.
- Guided participants in using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Express.js to start their web-based hackathon projects.

Skills

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Golang, SQL, Python, Java, VisualBasic.net (VB.net), C, C#, C++, Dart, Bash, AWK, CSS Technologies: Git, Docker, Docker Compose, Node.js, Deno, NPM, Remix.js, React.js, Gatsby.js, Angular.js, Express.js, Next.js, Preact.js, Solid.js, Svelte 3, Vite, Rollup, Webpack, Tailwind, Twind, SCSS, Styled Components, Fresh, UNIX, WSL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Flyctl, Prometheus, Grafana, Progressive Web Applications (PWA)

Productivity: JIRA, Figma, Notion, Microsoft Teams, Trello, Slite, Slack

Projects

| attach | (https://attach.fly.dev)

August 2022

Web Application

- A **Solid.js** contact sharing website styled with **Tailwind** that has full customization, a sleek design, multiple themes, a first contentful paint of 0.9s on a slow wifi,
- Manages server data with an Express.js backend that uses cron jobs to back up the state every 30s and collects different web statistics.

Portfolio (https://zackaryjamessantana.com)

July 2022

Web Application

• A **Fresh** app with uses **Deno** as a runtime that SSR (Server-Side Renders) **Preact.js** and **Twind** (just-in-time compiler for Tailwind) to provide a user experience with minimal client side ran JavaScript.